<u>MANAN JOSHI</u>

HOTEL OPERATIONS MANAGER

ABOUT ME

Customer-oriented Operations Manager with 9 years of experience focused on increasing revenues and expanding margin. Adaptive and deadline-oriented consistently executes and completes multiple projects in high-stress environments Serviced-focused operations manager dedicated to delivering positive customer experiences to promote loyalty and repeat business.. Sales leader with sound judgment, good planning abilities and interpersonal communication strengths.

Experience

Hotel Operation Manager, Jan 2019 – Aug 2021 **Dolphin Suites – Kampala**

- Drove year-over-year business growth while leading operations, strategic vision and long-range planning.
- Established and administered annual budget with controls to prevent overages, minimize burn rate and support sustainability objectives.
- Enhanced operational efficiency and productivity by managing budgets, accounts and costs.
- Assessed reports to evaluate performance develop targeted improvements and implement changes.
- Maximized efficiency by coaching and mentoring personnel on management principles, industry practices, company procedures and technology systems.
- Boosted productivity by consolidating material planning, data collecting and accounting programs into one main system.
- Organized budgets, oversaw P&Ls and achieved margin targets consistently to stay on track with growth plans.
- Reduced costs managed delivery schedules and performed risk analysis to improve overall profitability.

Front Office Manager, 2018 – 2019

Lemon Tree Hotel - Ahmedabad

- Coached employees through day-to-day work and complex problems.
- Communicated corporate objectives across divisions through regular correspondence and scheduled status updates.
- Interpreted management directives to define and document administrative staff processes.
- Oversaw quality control and productivity rates to increase revenue and production times.
- Achieved specific team objectives and collection activity.
- Monitor and Maintain OTA inventory and rates on regular basis.

Asst. Front Office Manager, 2016 – 2018 ITC Fortune Park Hotel – Ahmedabad

- Participated in team-building activities to enhance working relationships.
- Performed duties in accordance with applicable standards, policies and regulatory guidelines to promote safe working environment.
- Maintained excellent attendance record, consistently arriving to work on time.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Improved operations through consistent hard work and dedication.



Contact

Address

Vadodara, India - 390021

Phone

+91 - 9173445599

Email

Mananjoshi09@gmail.com

Skills

Language

English, Hindi, Gujarati, Kutchi

Computer

Opera, Fidelio, IDS, MS Office

Interpersonal

Analytical Mind, Recruitment, Team Leadership, Food Preparation and safety, Policy and Procedure adherence, Coaching and Mentoring, Relationship Building, Operations Management

Business

Sales expertise, Business Development, Project Management, Strategic Planning and Analysis, Consistently achieve goal, marketing,

Duty Manager, 2014 – 2016

The Gateway Hotel, Taj (Now Vivanta by Taj) - Vadodara

- Trained employees in essential job functions.
- Responded to customer concerns by providing friendly, knowledgeable support and maintaining composure and professionalism.
- Set goals for department and supported employees in meeting expectations.
- Responsible for front office, Travel Desk, Business center & IT department.

Front Office Executive, 2012 – 2014

Renaissance Marriott - Mumbai

- Responsible for Pre arrival and Check in/Check out of VIPs' and VVIP's
- Solving Guest Complain.
- Attending guest gueries via Phone and Email
- Cashiering.
- Achieving Targets of Up selling room and other services.
- Preparation of pre arrival, Check in, Checkout of all the Crew coming to the hotel

Educations and Training

2009 - 201 **Bsc Hospitality & Hotel Administration**

SIHM-KOZHIKODE

National Council of Hotel Management and Catering Technology

Percent: 71.4%

2010 **Hotel Sahara Star**

17 Weeks Industrial Training Core departments

2011 Welcom Hotel (ITC)

4 Weeks Vocational Training Front Office Department

Achievement

- Successfully achieved 94% of target, Highest since last 5 years, Year 2019
- Received for excellence and drive for customer satisfaction for moving hotel rank on Trip Advisor.
- Awarded for up selling target of INR 2,50,000/-, Year 2013
- Awarded for best groomed employee, Year 2012

Reference

Dharampal Singh Rathore

General Manager, Forest Cottage, Kampala, Uganda,

Phone: +256-709705821

Tejas Patel

Financial Controller, Golden Tulip, Dare Salam, Tanzania Phone: +255-709705821

Sven Saint-Calbre

General Manager, Hotel Latitude 0, Kampala, Uganda,

Phone: +256-757117813